

# SAUGAT RIMAL

WEB DESIGNER

 $\times$  +  $\times$ 

## CANDIDATE PROFILE

A web designer/developer focused on crafting great web experiences. I am a self taught developer, FOSS lover, linux enthusiast. I am highly motivated and very imaginative by finding inspirations in everyday things, pushing my own boundaries and allowing myself to think out of the box.

## **TOOLS & PLATFORMS**

- Wordpress & Ghost
- Html, Css & Javascript
  - Vercel & Cloudflare
    - -Gatsby & Netlify
    - Gitlab & Github
  - VScode & Sublime
    - Figma & Canva

## CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell: +977-98190989 mail@saugatrimal.com.np www.saugatrimal.com.np Biratnagar, Nepal

## EDUCATIONAL PROFILE

## **PURBANCHAL UNIVERSITY**

BACHELOR'S DEGREE | COMPUTER ENGINEERING

#### PANCHAYAT SECONDARY SCHOOL

DIPLOMA | CIVIL ENGINEERING

## PROJECTS

## **MY PROJECTS WORKS**

POLYWORK.COM / SAUGATRIMAL

- Specializes in building (and occasionally designing) exceptional digital experiences and focused on building accessible, human-centered products.
- View my all projects from the site given below
- https://timeline.saugatrimal.engineer

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### JUNIOR WORDPRESS DEVELOPER

SWIVT TECHNOLOGIES

Oct 2021 - Present

#### **WORDPRESS DEVELOPER**

HYBURTECH

May 2021 - Oct 2021

#### **WEB DESIGNER**

DANFE CREATIVES

April 2020 - Dec 2020

## SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Logical Thinking
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Googling
- Oral Communication
- Problem Solving

## EXPERIENCE COLLECTED

# JUNIOR WP DEVELOPER @ SWIVT TECHNOLOGIES

OCT 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed and maintained websites for in-house websites primarily using CMS like WordPress, Woo-Commerce, and others plugins
- Helped senior developers to write modern, performant, maintainable code for a diverse array of client and internal projects
- Worked with a team of designers & developers to build exceptional digital experiences.
- Communicate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, and clients on a daily basis

# WORDPRESS DEVELOPER @ HYBURTECH

MAY 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

- Work with a variety of different languages, platforms, frameworks, and CMS
- Interfaced with user experience designers and other developers to ensure thoughtful and coherent user experiences
- Architected and implemented various digital marketing statragies for clients to increase the traffic on webpages and products
- Worked with a team of four developers & designers to build a blog websites, marketing website and e-commerce platform, an ambitious startup
- Contributed on making the sites developed more SEO friendly along with SEO expert
- Increased the performance and speed of web pages which helps ranking the pages in top.

## WEB DESIGNER @ DANFE CREATIVES

APRIL 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

- Developed and maintained websites for in-house and client websites primarily using CMS like Wordpress, Ghost, Woo-Commerce and others form scratch
- Manually tested sites in various browsers and mobile devices to ensure crossbrowser compatibility and responsiveness
- Clients included Modern Decks an International Company, The MoonSun Group an Investment Company, GS Bazzar a Multi-Vendor, Nepal Art Gallary a Project Showcase for artist and more..
- Interfaced with clients on a weekly basis, providing technological expertise